ROY MUSTANG: The Freezing Alchemist?
Really? He's here?
BRADLEY: We have information that he managed
to slip into Central a few days ago.
That's why I've summoned you here, Colonel.
I need you and your men to smoke
him out and bring him in.
Consider it done, sir.
[BRADLEY CHUCKLES]
BRADLEY: I'm glad you're with us in Central
for awhile, Mustang.
It's good to know I have
people here I can count on.
- Sir.
- Uh, one last thing...
Our rising young star is here as well.
I'm placing him at your disposal.
Forgive me, Fuhrer Bradley,
but just to be clear, are you referring to...
I am.
I am the Fullmetal Alchemist, Edward Elric.
Ah, damn it.
The Colonel's never gonna
let us out of here, is he?
We already bought
our tickets for Liore, too.
Does this mean we're not going?
I don't know, Al.
For now, let's just get this over with.
- Okay?
- Mmm.
Lead the way, brother.
Kono omoi wo keshite shimau niwa
mada jinsei nagai dsho?
Yarinokoshite'ru koto
yarinaoshite mitai kara
Yume no tsuzuki oikakete ita hazu na no ni
Magarikunetta
hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
Ano koro mitai ni tte modoritai wake ja nai ni
Nakushite kita sora wo sagashite'ru
Wakatte kuremasu you ni
Gisei ni natta you na
kanashii kao wa yamete yo
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
Zutto kurushiku seotte'ku n da
Deguchi mienai kanjou meiro ni
dare wo matte'ru no?
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta you ni
motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
Nani kar nogaretai n da
genjitsu tte yatsu?
Kanaeru tame ni ikite'ru n datte
Sakebitaku naru yo Kikoete imasu ka?
Bunai n nante yatte'rarenai kara
...kaeru basho mo nai no
Yasashisa niwa itsumo kansha shite'ru
Dakara tsuyoku naritai
(I'm on the way)
Natsukashiku naru
konna itami mo kangei jan
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
[FOOTSTEPS]
There he goes, that way!
You, halt! Halt or I'll shoot!
[YELLING]
Ah!
[BODY THUDS]
Water freezes, water boils.
Either way, you're just as dead.
That's alchemy.
ED: What a nasty thing to do.
You of all people should know,
great deeds required great sacrifice.
Isn't that the law equivalent exchange?
Save your breath, the laws of alchemy
don't justify murder!
No transmutation circle!
Don't be too impressed.
Now!
What?!
No, I had you!
Any water there should've boiled!
If it's any consolation,
you did ruin my coat.
An automail arm!
A young gifted alchemist...
One who doesn't use transmutation circles...
And who has an auto mail right arm!
I know you.
You are the Fullmetal Alchemist,
Edward Elric!
So...it's not you?
Oh...um, no!
I'm his younger brother, Alphonse.
But he's a runt!
Oh, yeah?! Can runt do this?!
I've heard the stories,
but still I never imagined this.
The Fullmetal Alchemist
is just a little kid!
Don't call me little!
You know brother, I don't think he was
really talking about your height just now.
Well even if he wasn't, he still pissed me off!
So you're the one we've been
hearing all the stories about lately!
The Fullmetal Alchemist!
You're as good as they say,
thanks for the help.
Um, you're welcome, but...
I'm really not the one you should be thanking.
There.
C'mon, let's get going Al.
We got a train to catch.
Oh, okay! Um...
if you think it's alright to leave...
[THUD]
[GASPS]
What is that?! Steam?
Brother, he's gone!
Damn it, now he really pissed me off!
MUSTANG: Looks like you underestimated
your opponent, Fullmetal.
Who is this guy anyway?
You'd know that if you'd listen
to the briefing like I told you to.
But no, you had to go
charging right after him—
Yeah, yeah, I get it, alright?
I'm sorry, 'kay? Whatever.
Next time a superior tells you
to pay attention, you might just try it.
Fine.
Now then, his name is Isaac McDougal.
Or he was known back in the day,
Isaac the Freezer.
He's a former State Alchemist.
ED: Former?
That's right.
He served in the Ishvalan war.
During that time, he gave us
no signs that he'd turned traitor.
But after, he immediately resigned
his commission and went into hiding.
He's been working with the
anti-establishment movement ever since.
Taking him into custody
is a matter of top priority.
Whether it's dead or alive,
that's up to him.
No way, I'm not killing anyone for you.
And that's your choice.
Your orders are simply to
help us contain him.
That's all.
[CHUCKLES] Off topic...
Have you turned up any leads
for getting your bodies back to normal?
Maybe if you ever gave us time to look!
Roy! How goes?
Heard you let him put you in
charge of catching the Freezer, huh?
One hell of an nasty assignment.
But hey, could be your chance
to earn that promotion to Central.
Oh, say!
Looks like my timing was perfect!
You two are the Elric brothers, right?
ED: Huh?
Wow, it's an honor to finally meet
the youngest State Alchemist ever.
You're a real legend around here!
I'm Lieutenant Colonel Maes Hughes, a pleasure.
Um...you want Edward!
I'm actually his younger brother, Alphonse.
What?! You're the Fullmetal Alchemist?
Sorry, I had no idea you would be so...
Go on, say little. I dare you.
MUSTANG: Hughes.
Yeah?
What are you doing here?
Go home.
Actually, I'm here on official business.
You, Elrics, I understand that
you two don't have a place to stay.
Which means you'll have to come with me.
BOTH: Huh?
BOTH: Ah!
My wife, Gracia and my daughter, Elicia.
We'd love to have you!
Hi, Princess!
[ELICIA GIGGLING]
Ow! Daddy, your beard is itchy!
[LAUGHS]
Like this?
Itchy! Itchy!
[BOTH GIGGLING]
HUGHES: Look, we have guests!
These are the Elric brothers.
Big brother!
Little brother!
Nice to meet you. My name is Edward Elric.
This is my younger brother, Alphonse Elric.
Get that?
[EMPHASIZING] Young-er broth-er.
But younger means little...
You're little!
AL: Just let it go Ed...
ED: Where do you get off calling me little?!
AL: These people are being nice to let us stay here!
ED: You look in the mirror lately?!
HUGHES: Hope you boys are hungry.
Gracia's cooking his delicious!
Huh?!
ED: Ah...!
[ELICIA GIGGLING]
Okay, eat up.
Thanks!
Wow, you weren't kidding!
This is great!
GRACIA: Don't be shy. Eat all you want!
ED: Okay!
AL: [GIGGLES]
Alphonse, how you're going to eat
wearing that armor? Take it off, relax!
BOTH: Uh...
Well, you see...uh—
He's not allowed to!
He has to wear it all the time.
It's uh...
It's part of his alchemy training!
[NERVOUS LAUGH]
You know how it is.
I'll eat enough for both of us.
Training, choo-choo!
Translation: "Central Prison"
[MAN LAUGHING]
KIMBLEE: Hands down that's got to be the funniest
joke I've heard in a long, long time.
The Freezing Alchemist wants
me to come play his sidekick.
Well as fun as that sounds,
The Crimson Alchemist works alone,
I always have.
Kimblee, if we work together we can bring
down Bradley and his godforsaken military.
You saw the horrors
that took place in Ishval
You were there, dammit!
You know the things
Bradley ordered us to do.
The kind of man he really is.
That's why you killed all those officers, isn't it?
To send him a message?
[CACKLING]
I think you've got me all wrong.
My motives aren't so sophisticated
as revenge or honor any of that.
The reason I killed all of those men
was because I could.
It's that simple.
That's too bad, Kimblee.
[FOOTSTEPS LEAVING]
That truly is too bad.
[PRISON DOORS OPEN AND CLOSING]
Keep up the good work.
[BODY SMASHES]
[DOOR OPENS]
Maes, dear...what's wrong?
Can't sleep?
Guess not.
I know it's in that head of yours.
You're worrying about
those boys, aren't you?
You do know what they call
State Alchemists, right?
The dogs of the military,
not exactly the most popular bunch.
I try to imagine what that must be like,
enduring that at his age.
Brother, you awake?
Huh?
Miss Gracia's quiche...
It looked a lot like moms, huh?
Yeah, almost as good too.
Really?!
In that case, I'm definitely adding it to the list
of things I'm gonna eat once I get my body back!
Right.
Put it on there, right near the top.
AL: Brother?
ED: Hmm?
AL: I sure would like to get
our old bodies back soon.
ED: I know. Me too.
MCDOUGAL: One more.
One more and Fuhrer
Bradley is on his way to hell.
Fullmetal Alchemist
MUSTANG: We have a confirmed report that
McDougal broke into Central Prison last night.
Whatever he's up to, he's growing bold.
That means our time is short.
Close off all roads,
search every square inch of the city.
When you find him, shoot on sight.
That is an order from the Fuhrer himself.
But if I find him first...
He's mine.
Get a medic! Hurry!
Report to headquarters!
Five men dead!
How awful.
It looks like a steam explosion.
Raise the temperature of water fast enough
it expands with the force of a bomb blast.
And the human body is 70% water.
Let's hurry.
We have to find him
before he hurts anyone else.
Mmm!
Finished.
Impressive reflexes, Isaac,
few are able to dodge my alchemy so easily!
I know that voice.
Is that you, Armstrong?
Indeed!
None other.
It is I, the Strong Arm Alchemist,
Alex Louis Armstrong, in the flesh!
Ah, shut it!
I've always wanted to
chop that ego down to size.
Except you'll need far more
than water to quench my fists!
[GASPS]
AL: Major!
The water from his canteen, huh?
Thanks for the quick save, Al.
Let's go, he's getting away.
Come then, after me, Elric Brothers.
BOTH: Right!
It's been a long time, Freezer.
MCDOUGAL: Well, Roy Mustang.
Heh.
So the Flame Alchemist came out to play.
MUSTANG: You can make this easy on both of us.
I'd rather not fight an old war buddy.
War buddy? Please,
don't flatter yourself.
I knew no friends in Ishval.
Only military bastards,
and their damn dogs!
When water meets flame,
the flame goes out.
Dammit, ugh!
Still there! Perfect!
Stop right there!
I was wondering what you were doing
in this alley, so I came back to check it out,
And bingo!
[MCDOUGAL LAUGHS]
There's nowhere to run this time!
Clearly, but who's running?
[GASPS]
An alchemic reaction...
On this scale...
Impossible! Unless...
- AL: You don't think he's...?
A Philosopher's Stone!
He's freezing all the moisture in the air.
Edward, Elric.
You've sworn your life to the state
as a dog of the military,
But...
Do you really know the ones you serve
or what their true plans are?
Who cares?!
It's not my problem.
Don't be a fool!
He'll lead us to all ruin!
I'm only doing what needs to be done!
I told you, I don't care!
All right! Nice work, Al.
AL: But we still have to stop his alchemy!
ED: I know.
So where is it?
You have a Philosopher's Stone,
don't you?
What are you talking about?
I won't ask again. Where is it?!
And what are you going to do, boy?
You're out of your league!
Ahh!
Stand back and prepare for a
display of Armstrong alchemy!
He's all yours, Major!
Witness the alchemic art passed
down the Armstrong line for generations!
That's unexpected!
What the heck are you doing?!
You're making it worse!
No! I was merely—
[BOOM]
AL: The ice walls...
They're merging!
But, that would mean...
ED: If they all meet in the middle...
Ah, damn it!
It's Central Command!
BOTH: He's gonna freeze it over!
Major!
Al and I'll try to slow him down.
Can you handle the transmutation circles?
Consider them erased. I'm on it.
Fuhrer King Bradley,
For your cold-blooded crimes in Ishval,
I condemn you to a frozen hell.
- Not so fast!
- Huh?!
Two can play that game!
[ED YELPING]
Brother!
Too slow!
Alphonse!
There's no one in there...
It's empty!
But that...that could only be true
if his soul was bonded to the armor.
So you lost your arm,
and your brother, he lost his entire body?
Heh.
I see. It all makes sense.
You fools committed the ultimate taboo!
You attempted human
transmutation, didn't you?
Alchemy's one and only unforgivable sin!
[SCREAMING] Al!
Dammit! This can't be happening!
No!
He's gone! What I have done?!
[VOICE TREMBLING]
Give him back...
He's my brother!
Just give him back!
He's my little brother.
He's all I have left!
Y'know...
there are some lines you
really shouldn't cross.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
ED: Give it up!
There's no water for you to use here.
[LAUGHS]
You've forgotten something.
I have all the water I need...
70% of my body!
[GASPS]
Ed!
Why can't you fools understand?
I'm trying to save this country!
[CACKLING]
Brother...
Brother!
Come on. We're going after him.
I'm not done.
Not even close.
Did we get it?
[GASPS]
Not again!
What do you think of my flames
now, you bastard?!
When will he learn?
It's bad enough that he's useless on rainy days.
Huh?
Bradley.
[CACKLING MADLY]
Perfect!
[CONTINUES CACKLING]
[KIMBLEE CHUCKLES]
Now that is too bad.
Major, go now!
Leave it to me!
The Armstrong fist will not fail!
[ED PANTING]
ED: Fuhrer Bradley...You're here?
Ah, yes!
Job well done, Fullmetal.
I came out to see if I could lend a hand.
And to think...
that I'd actually
be the one to catch him.
If nothing else, this should
make an exciting story for my son!
[SNEEZE]
HUGHES: Ooh, is that a cold I hear?
Ah, never mind! From what I'm told
you're the man of the hour!
Nah, I just destroyed
the transmutation circles.
The Fuhrer is the one who
actually brought down McDougal.
Sure, but the Fuhrer's
telling everyone it was you!
So congratulations!
Oh, it's like that, huh?
Suit yourself, but some friendly advice...
Next time a superior tells you to take credit
for something you didn't do, you might try it for once.
We never did find out whether
or not he had a Philosopher's Stone.
AL: You know...
We never did find out whether
or not he had a Philosopher's Stone.
No, but maybe it'll say
something in the official report.
[KNOCKING AT DOOR]
BOTH: Hmm?
Greetings, Edward Elric.
When I heard you were in the hospital,
I dashed right over!
Ahh!
[BOTH WHIMPERING]
And as I suspected, you're in
desperate need of my assistance.
ARMSTRONG: A-ha!
[ED AND AL YELLING]
ARMSTRONG: You need the example of a perfect
physical specimen to inspire your recovery!
You see? You're looking lively already!
ED: Will you get out!
[ARMSTRONG LAUGHING]
Ah, I see. So Isaac's dead, is he?
That's a shame. I had such
high hopes for him, too.
But...the Philosopher's Stone?
[CHUCKLES]
Sounds like he overused it.
Gluttony, try to chew
quietly, I'm on the phone.
Yes, things are going well here in Liore.
We'll be ready.
It all begins very soon.
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora o
nee kimi wa oboete imasu ka
Yakusoku chigiri shoka
no kaze ga tsutsumu
futari yorisotta
Muri na egao no ura
nobita kage o kakumau
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei o erabu
Table no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
kuuhaku no yoru o kuru hazu no nai asa mo
zenbu wakatte'tan da
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora o
nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
Hatasenakatta yakusoku o idaite
futari arukidasu
Resembool, a quiet town.
The place where Edward and Alphonse were born.
The home they once shared with their mother.
In the hopes of returning to happier times, the boys commit
the ultimate taboo and are forced to confront the truth.
Next time on Fullmetal Alchemist: Brotherhood
Episode 2: The First Day
The day they resolved their hearts to begin the journey.